

Alessandra Maffei | Frontend Developer

Onckenstraße 19, 12059 Berlin, Germany +4915236210934 ales.maffei@gmail.com GitHub LinkedIn

Web/Frontend Developer with a growth mindset and a 10-year background in digital marketing for international tech companies and agencies. Hands-on experience in building web applications using JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, and React.js. Combines a passion for technology with the key qualities of a marketer: customer focus, effective cross-team collaboration, and an adaptable problem-solving approach to every task.

TECH STACK

HTML • CSS • JavaScript • TypeScript • ReactJS • Bootstrap • TailwindCSS • (on the backend, familiarity with Node.js • Express)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer (Apprenticeship) - The Collab Lab

Portfolio

MARCH 2023 - NOW

- Collaborate on a remote team of 4 early career Frontend Engineers guided by 2 Seniors
- Build components and features for a Progressive Web App using HTML, CSS, React, and Firestore
- Work in an Agile environment (syncs, retrospectives, and pair programming)

Full Stack Web and App Development Graduate - WBS Coding School, Berlin

OCTOBER 2022 - FEBRUARY 2023

- Participated in a full-time practice-oriented coding course (details under "Education")
- Delivered 7 weekly back-end and front-end projects

Social & Editorial Lead / Head of Media - <u>CareerFoundry</u>, Berlin

JANUARY 2020 - MARCH 2022

- Led a 12-people remote-first organic marketing team → delivered 40% of monthly revenue
- Improved SEO metrics for the <u>CF Blog</u> in collaboration with web developers → Google Speed Performance score increased from 60 to 98 on desktop
- Organized company-wide task production system for copy, design, and video content

Head of Social Media - Asana Rebel GmbH, Berlin

JUNE 2019 - JANUARY 2020

Established the Social Media Team (hiring, tooling, processes, personal training, career growth)

 Acted as the Marketing contact point towards Customer Support and QA Engineering to address feedback on product quality, flag bugs, and submit feature requests

Senior Social Media Manager - <u>Babbel (Lesson Nine GmbH)</u>, Berlin

MAY 2016 - MAY 2019

- Led the global team responsible for Babbel's growth on social media in 7 languages
- Set up the infrastructure for positive and smooth collaboration with Marketing, Customer Support, and Product: tooling, processes, documentation, reporting

(Further professional experiences can be found on LinkedIn)

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web and App Development Program - WBS Coding School

OCTOBER 2022 - FEBRUARY 2023

- Frontend: HTML5 CSS JavaScript (Fundamentals, DOM, Functional Programming, OOP) Open-source JavaScript frameworks (React) CSS preprocessors (SASS) and frameworks (Tailwind CSS)
- Backend: NodeJS/ExpressJS Overview APIs (REST, GraphQL) Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- Tools and version control: Console, GIT, and GitHub
- **Best practices**: Pair programming UX/UI Fundamentals Design system management Agile Methodologies (SCRUM)

MA Digital Communication - Sapienza Università di Roma

FEB 2009 - FEBRUARY 2011

BA Communication Sciences - Università degli studi Roma TRE

JUNE 2005 - JANUARY 2009

PROJECTS

- The Weather App | TypeScript, React, TailwindCSS, OpenWeather API
- Ask A Local | JavaScript, React, CSS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose
- Space Memory Game | JavaScript, React, CSS, Pexel Photo API
- Nonna's Cookbook | JavaScript, React, CSS, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL

(All projects are linked in my portfolio)

TOOLS

- Project-task management | Jira, Asana, Trello
- Collaboration | Miro, Mural, Figma
- Communication and documentation | Confluence, Notion, Loom
- Monitoring and reporting | Google Analytics, Tableau, Hotjar